

Vorathip Phitakkhet

IT Manager, Project Management

Having been graduated with a Bachelor's Degree from Kasetsart University and worked as a software developer with over 10 years of experience performing multi-function management including project manager, system analyst, and application support. I currently work as IT Project Management Manager at BCI (Thailand) with a goal of standardizing and rollout of the core operating system. Seeking challenging positions with more involvement of business and management in any field and industry to apply my expertise and adaptable personality to fulfill business needs.

PERSONAL DETAILS NICKNA

NICKNAME: FIRST

BIRTHDAY: AUGUST 13, 1989

GENDER: WOMEN

MOBILE: +66970129986

EMAIL: Vorathip.ph@gmail.com

NATIONALITY: THAI

LIVE IN: BANGKOK, THAILAND

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology KASETSART UNIVERSITY (2009-2012)

SKILLS

- ☺ PROJECT MANAGEMENT ☺ STRATEGIC THINKING ☺ PROBLEM-SOLVING
- STRONG SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT
 □ LANGUAGE TH/EN
 □ COACHING
- ☺ NETWORK IMPLEMENTATION ☺ SYSTEM EVALUATION

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

BCI (Thailand) Co., LTD.

IT Project Management Manager, September 2020 - Present

- Setting project goals and coming up with plans to meet those goals
- Maintaining project timeframes, budgeting estimates, and status reports
- Managing resources for projects, such as computer equipment and employees
- Coordinating project team members and developing schedules and individual responsibilities
- Implementing IT strategies that deliver projects on schedule and within budget
- Using project management tools to track project performance and schedule adherence

- Conducting risk assessments for projects
- Organizing meetings to discuss project goals and progress

KERRY Logistics (Thailand) Co., LTD.

IT Manager, June 2020 – September 2021

- Analyst the application operation Logistics and good knowledge in the application
 architecture and infrastructure that support those applications and prepare
 project timeline with the scope of work.
- Troubleshooting the issues of those servers and networks and applications, identifying the root causes, and initiating the problem-solving methods. Then recommend the solution to prevent the problem.
- Working closely with the HK IT Team to completed the IT service requested and ensure aligned KLN IT Standard.
- Working closely with the Application, IT support, and Analyst programmer team to deliver quality IT applications to the users.
- The highly complex solution and control overall architecture of the IT Infrastructure that requires 99.99% uptime to support IT Infrastructure of the Kerry Logistics.
- Supervising and coaching the team of Kerry Logistics
- Managed automation system projects as a project manager. This included creating
 proposals and TOR, defining the scope of work, vendor selection, project timeline,
 and budget appraisal, throughout the delivery of solution and training
- Designed overall project infrastructure; server and database specifications, communication networks and protocols, and developing software according to users' requirements and core businesses. Troubleshoot application issues and release new application versions based on solved issues and specific differences between clients.

KERRY EXPRESS (Thailand) Co., LTD.

Regional Application Team lead, September 2018 – June 2020

- Mainly responsible as a team lead application support for regional IT division
- Globally standardize operational processes and IT system
- Possessing specialist knowledge of operating systems, devices, applications, and software
- To support 5 countries (Malaysia, Indonesia, Vietnam, Cambodia, Hongkong)
- Assign tasks or tickets to teams
- Providing technical support to teams within the organization and to external clients when required
- Assisting with system integrations
- Managing ticketed query system and ensuring comprehensive database of queries and resolutions is kept up to date
- Maintaining and updating technical documentation and procedures

- Identifying and resolving technical issues
- Managing coordination at a local and international level where required
- Preparing maintenance plans and upgrading scheduled for the organization's systems
- Developing reports for teams across the business
- Setup Training Course for the team. For example; SQL Command, Performance Tuning
- Maintenance Server Plan App and Database
- Monitor server performance and investigate any issues
- Provide presentation for the present to all related

THE ROYAL BANK OF SCOTLAND

Software Developer Specialist, January 2015 – April 2017

- Enhance program both of web app and win app using .NET (C#, VB), PHP, HTML
- Solved problem coding and error
- Development life cycle (BPR, Unit Test, UAT, Deployment, User Manual)
- Daily report, re-run, and recovery process
- Analyzes and designed system based upon system architectural direction and user requirements
- Enhancement and development DMS website to generate a report, XML file sends to Bank of Thailand (BOT)
- Able to train end-user
- To design database structure and design user interface including ER-diagram, Data Dictionary, etc.
- Security Control: To manage users for access to Bank of Thailand systems such as ITMX, ICAS, DMS, TDID Certificate

TOYOTOMI AUTO PARTS (THAILAND) CO., LTD

Software Developer, October 2013 – December 2014

- Main PIC to develop internal software
- Using .NET Programming, jQuery Mobile
- Analyzed, designed, and implemented by using Visual Studio, PL/SQL
- Solve problem coding and error on the Application system
- Develop auto sending report from database
- Document: System Document, User Document
- Maintain and support ERP system in manufacturing
- Have knowledge in infrastructure such as Network, Server, Support, etc.
- Responsible for a new project in the company.
- Able to train users about in-house programs and ERP system

SONY TECHNOLOGY (THAILAND) CO., LTD

IT Specialist (Programmer), April 2012 – August 2013

- Develop system using .Net Programming
- Analyzes and document software systems based upon system architectural
- direction and user requirements
- Create and modifies process models, including state, class, activity,
- communication and deployment diagrams (BPR)
- Provides training in computer languages, process modeling, and software
- documentation
- Provides training for end users as needed audits programming project as
- assigned
- Provide timely progress reports on various assigned projects
- Recommends system development procedure and standards
- Attends meetings and may call special meeting with end user